Vonnegut, Bernard; Papers ua902.068
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Bernard Vonnegut Papers
1828-1997
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
ua902.068
39.04 cubic ft.
The Bernard Vonnegut Papers document Vonnegut's career as a researcher in the field of atmospheric science with a focus on his time at GE, Arthur Little, and the State University of New York at Albany. The collection includes technical memoranda, research, data, inventions and patent forms, equipment specifications, drawings, figures, handwritten notes, manuscripts, reports, correspondence, publicity materials, course materials, news clippings, photographs, memorabilia, and audio/video materials
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted with the exception of select folders that are marked on the inventory. Researchers with inquiries about this material should contact the head of archives.
Acquisition Information
The Bernard Vonnegut papers were donated to M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives by Sally Marsh, Dr. Vonnegut's administrative assistant, in July 2005.
Biographical Sketch
Dr. Bernard Vonnegut was born in 1914 in Indianapolis, Indiana to architect Kurt Vonnegut, Sr. (1884-1957) and Edith Sophia Lieber (d. 1944). He had two younger siblings; a sister, Alice (1917-1958), and a brother, Kurt (1922-2007), the 20th Century author famous for his works of satire and science fiction. Bernard Vonnegut attended public elementary schools, Shortridge High School and the Park School which he graduated from in 1932. From there he attended MIT, the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, where he earned his bachelor's degree in Chemistry in 1936 and a doctorate in Physical Chemistry in 1939.
After receiving his PhD, Vonnegut went to work for the Hartford Empire Company where he conducted research on surface properties and the breaking stress of glass. He worked there for two years before returing to MIT as a research associate. During his time as a research associate, Vonnegut worked in the Chemical Engineering Department as well as the Meteorology Department. His research in the Chemical Engineering Department focused on aerosol generation, filtration, and measurement while in the Meteorological Department he researched icing of aircrafts, the adhesion of ice, and the properties of supercooled clouds.
In 1945, Vonnegut left MIT once again and went to work for GE Research Labortories. At first he worked in the chemistry group where he focused on the supercooling of liquid tin metals but then was moved to another department. In his new position, Vonnegut worked alongside Nobel laureate Dr. Irving Langmuir, and Vincent J. Schaefer, the original discoverer of cloud seeding via dry ice. With Langmuir and Schaefer, Vonnegut worked on cloud seeding and problems related to cloud physics as well as Project Cirrus, a weather modification program. Research on Project Cirrus was done in conjunction with the United States Signal Corps, Office of Naval Research, and the United States Air Force. General oversight was handled by the Department of Defense. The objective of the project was to find ways to artificially influence precipitation. Work on this project, as well as the science of artificial precipitation, was strongly influenced by Vonnegut's discovery of AgI, Silver Iodide, as a superior nucleation agent. This method became the chief method of "rain making." Along with his discovery of AgI as a nucleation agent, Vonnegut also devised intruments for measuring the true air temperature from an airplane, known as the vortex thermometer, and an automatic condensation nucei meter for measuring aerosols.
Dr. Vonnegut left GE in 1952 for a position with the management consultant angency Arthur D. Little where he continued research in atmospheric science and aerosols. His atmospheric science research was done in partnership with Charles Moore; their work was focused on atmospheric electricity and cloud physics. While at Arthur D. Little, Dr. Vonnegut also participated in research on the problems associated with the measurement and production of aerosols, the miniaturization of electrical recorders, the hazards of electrostatic in industry, glass fiber formation, and the behavior of evaporating electrified droplets. Much of the reaearch and experiments that Vonnegut conducted at Arthur Little were not done purely for research purposes but done because of contracts the company had with public and private agencies.
After 15 years with Arthur D. Little, Dr. Vonnegut moved on to the newly created Atmospheric Sciences Research Center at the State University of New York at Albany under the direction of Vincent Schaefer. Vonnegut was hired as a senior research scientist and looked at electrification in thunderstorms, the role of electricity in precipitation formation, and kinetic nucleation. Along with his research position, Vonegut also held an academic appointment in which he taught classes on atmospheric electricity, atmospheric instrumentation, and atmospheric chemistry. During his time at SUNY Albany, Vonnegut received several awards. In 1976, he was awarded the American Meteorological Award for Outstanding Contributions to the Advancement of Applied Meteoroloy. The following year, he recieved the Weather Modification Association Vincent J. Schaefer Award. Along with these awards, Vonnegut was named a Distinguished Research Professor in 1984 and, upon his formal retirement in 1985, was named Professor Emeritus.
One of Dr. Vonnegut's most notable projects during his time at SUNY Albany was his collaboration with NASA on the Night/Day Optical Survey of Lightning (NOSL) experiments. Astronauts, equipped with specialized recording instruments, took pictures and video of large thunderstorms over the course of three shuttle missions. Dr. Vonnegut, who proposed the project, utilized the photographs and data in his continuing research on thunderstorms and electrification theory.
Throughout his career, Dr. Vonnegut pursued research in many fields of interest; mainly thunderclouds, tornadoes, and lightning. He made regular summer expeditions to New Mexico where he worked with colleagues at the New Mexico Institute of Mining and Technology in Socorro to study these phenomena, and many of the experiments he undertook pertain to these three topics. Furthermore, Dr. Vonnegut accumulated multiple patents for his inventions and research techniques.
Dr. Vonnegut married Lois Bowler (d. 1972) and had five sons. Interestingly, after becoming a father, he took on a personal campaign to improve the quality of educational science texts and encyclopedias, as well as truth in advertising regarding scientific claims on children's products.
Dr. Vonnegut continued atmospheric research and publishing until his death from cancer at 82 in 1997.
Scope and Contents
Dr. Vonnegut's papers chronicle his professional career as an atmospheric scientist at MIT, the GE Research Laboratories, Arthur D. Little Corporation, and the State University of New York at Albany's Atmospheric Sciences Research Center and Department of Atmospheric Sciences. The collection spans from 1828 his death in 1997. The earliest materials in the collection are reprints of articles that he referenced for his research.
The records in this collection document Dr. Vonnegut's research interests. These interests include icing and atmospheric electricity, cloud physics, thunderstorms, and tornado formation. The collection also contain extensive information about his major scientific discoveries and experiments, such as Project Cirrus, a program that sought ways to artificially influence precipitation, the NASA/NOSL project where he studied weather phenomena from space, and his experiments and research in New Mexico. Additionally, a small amount of personal records are interspersed in the collection.
The collection is arranged into 11 series. The records consist of technical memoranda, research, data, inventions and patent forms, equipment specifications, drawings, figures, handwritten notes, manuscripts, reports, correspondence, publicity materials, course materials, news clippings, photographs, memorabilia, and audio/video materials. The majority of materials date from Dr. Vonnegut's tenure at GE, Arthur D. Little, and State University of New York at Albany.
All series are arranged alphabetically and reflect Dr. Vonnegut's own filing system. Since the original order was maintained, correspondence is kept with other materials, such as reports and technical memorandum, when they were found together. If the correspondence was found in a seperate place than the materials it was originally meant to be paired with, there was not an effort to reunite the materials. Copies of reports and memorandum may be found in multiple locations.
For related materials, please see the following collections held by the ME Grenander Department of Special Collection and Archives: Atmospheric Sciences Research Center Records (UA-450), which includes many publications and articles issued by the ASRC, Duncan Blanchard Papers (UA-902.065), Raymond Falconer Papers (UA-902.014) and Vincent J. Schaefer (UA-902.010).
Separated Materials
Archivists transfered the monographs The Final Report of the Advisory Committee on Weather Control (Volumes 1 and 2) and Weather Control and Augmented Potable Water Supply. Joint Hearings Before...(Joint Hearings on Weather Control) to the book division of Special Collections. The catalog records for these monographs is included in Minerva, the University Library Catalog.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
All series are arranged alphabetically.
Conservation and the Environment; Aerosols; Atmospheric electricity; Atmospheric physics; Cloud physics; Clouds--Dynamics; Columbia (Spacecraft); Consulting contracts; Electrostatics; Lightning; Rain-making; Silver Iodide; Thunderstorm electricity; Tornadoes; Volcanoes--Iceland; Weather control; Albany (N.Y.); Cambridge (M.A.); Indianapolis (I.L.); Washington, Mount (N.H.); Mount Washington Observatory; Mount Withington (N.M.); Schenectady (N.Y.); Socorro (N.M.); Surtsey (island); Administrative reports; Annual reports; Charts; Correspondence; Diagrams; Manuscripts (document genre); Maps; Memorabilia; Newsletters; Newspaper clippings; Notes; Papers; Photographs; Slides (photographs); Sound recordings; Technical reports; Transparencies; Video recordings; UAlbany Faculty & Alumni Papers; Blanchard, Duncan C.; Brook, Marx; Langmuir, Irving, 1881-1957; Moore, Charles B., 1920-2010; Schaefer, Vincent J.; Vonnegut, Bernard; Vaughan, Otha H.; Arthur D. Little, Inc.; General Electric Company; Massachusetts Institute of Technology; New Mexico Institute of Mining and Technology; State University of New York. Atmospheric Sciences Research Center; United States. National Aeronautics and Space Administration; U.S. Army Signal Engineering Laboratories
- Project Cirrus, 1891-1985; Undated; 1; 4.25 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series documents the Project Cirrus program, a weather modification initiative undertaken by GE along with the United States Signal Corps, Office of Naval Research, and the United States Air Force, with general oversight handled by the Department of Defense. As part of the effort, Dr. Vonnegut discovered that AgI, Silver Iodide, was a superior nucleation agent. This discovery significantly influenced the science of artificial precipitation and this method came to be adopted as the chief means of "rain making".
  The series contains the research, data, reports, correspondence, publicity, and photographs regarding the project. Please note that the archivist filed all of the loose photographs together. The archivist kept any photograph accompanying research, data, or reports with that respective material.
  - AgI, Silver Iodide Chemical Reviewer Article, 1949 (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 1)
  - AgI, Silver Iodide Cloud Seeding, Undated (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 2)
  - AgI, Silver Iodide, Conductive Silver Preparations, Undated (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 3)
  - AgI, Silver Iodide, Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 4)
  - AgI, Silver Iodide Drawings and Photographs, Undated (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 5)
  - AgI, Silver Iodide Seeding Transparencies, Undated (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 6)
  - AgI, Silver Iodide Smoke Generators, 1950 (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 7)
  - AgI, Silver Iodide Smokes and Generators, 1948 (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 8)
  - AgI, Silver Iodide, Rough Drafts, 1949; 1951 (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 9)
  - Conferences, Committee on Snow and Ice Tentative Classifications, Undated (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 10)
  - Conferences, On Interfacial Phenomena and Nucleation, 1951 (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 11)
  - Conferences, Regarding CloudSeeding, 1950 (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 12)
  - Data, Catalogue of Data for Project Cirrus, 1950 (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 13)
  - Data, Efficiency of Natural and Artificial Freezing Nucleo Chart, Undated (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 14)
  - Data, Fourth Partial Report, Undated (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 15)
  - Data, GE Research Notepad July 19,20 and 22, 1949 (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 16)
  - Data, GE Research Notepad July 21, 23, 1949 (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 17)
  - Data, New Mexico Flights, 1950 (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 18)
  - Data, Notepad - Flight Notes Friday July 15, Undated (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 19)
  - Data Project Cirrus Personnel and Expenses, 1949 (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 20)
  - Data, Puerto Rico Flight Map, 1947 (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 21)
  - Data, Spiral Notebook, AgI Notes, Undated (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 22)
  - Data, Temperature and Air Speed Charts, Undated (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 23)
  - Data, Temperature and Air Speed Charts, M2 Thermometer Housing, Undated (Oversized 4, Folder 1)
  - History, Annotated Project Cirrus History, Undated (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 24)
  - History, History of Cloud Seeding, 1979 (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 25)
  - History, History of Project Cirrus, 1952 (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 26)
  - History, Project Cirrus History Correspondence, Drafts and Photos, 1974-1985 (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 27)
  - History, Project Cirrus The Story of Cloud Seeding, 1952 (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 28)
  - Legislation, Extracts from Hearings on Weather Modification Proceedings, 1951 (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 29)
  - Legislation, House Subcommittee on Weather Modification Proceedings, 1951 (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 30)
  - Legislation, NYS Weather Modification Legislation, 1950 (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 31)
  - Legislation, UN Report - Economic Aspects of Experimental Meteorology, 1949 (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 32)
  - Legislation, U.S. Dept. of Commerce Reports, 1948 (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 33)
  - Legislation, U.S. Weather Control Memorandum, 1952 (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 34)
  - Measurement Apparatus, Air Speed/Temperature, 1936-1937; 1942; 1947-1952; 1954; 1959-1960 (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 35)
  - Measurement Apparatus, Air Speed/Temperature, Undated (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 36)
  - Measurement Apparatus, Capillary Collector, 1945; 1948 (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 37)
  - Measurement Apparatus, Cloud Chamber, Undated (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 38)
  - Measurement Apparatus, Condensation Nuclei Counter, 1949 (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 39)
  - Measurement Apparatus, Vortex Thermometer Charts and Graphs, Undated (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 40)
  - Measurement Apparatus, Vortex Thermometer Flight Data, 1956 (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 41)
  - Measurement Apparatus, Vortex Thermometer Report, 1949 (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 42)
  - New Research Laboratory, Undated (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 43)
  - Patents, 1948-1952 (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 44)
  - Patents, 1948-1951 (Oversized 3, Folder 1)
  - Photos, Clouds and Tools, 1949-1950; Undated (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 45)
  - Photos, Colored Cloud Slides, Undated (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 46)
  - Photos, Flight #57, 1948; Undated (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 47)
  - Photos, Flight #105, 1949 (Box 1 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 48-50)
  - Photos, Flight #105 Camera Report, 1949 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 1)
  - Photos, GE Personnel and Clouds, 1949-1950 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 2)
  - Photos, Negatives - Assorted, 1950; Undated (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 3)
  - Photos, New Mexico, 1949; 1973 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 4)
  - Photos, Plane/Flight Crew and Puerto Rico, 1948-1950 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 5)
  - Photos, Puerto Rico, 1949 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 6)
  - Photos, Reference, 1943; 1946; 1950; 1952; 1973 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 7)
  - Photos, Seeding Path, 1948 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 8)
  - Photos, Silver Iodide, Undated (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 9)
  - Photos, Silver Iodide Generators, Undated (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 10)
  - Photos, Water Droplets and Smoke Particles, Undated (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 11)
  - Project Cirrus History - Final Reports, 1952-1955 (Oversized 5)
  - Project Cirrus Meteorological Research - Occassional Reports, 1947-1953 (Oversized 6)
  - Project Cirrus Scrapbook, 1946-1948; 1950-1951; 1960; Undated (Oversized 2)
  - Project Cirrus Scrapbook, Undated (Oversized 3, Folder 2)
  - Publicity, AMS Dispute Letter, 1951 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 12)
  - Publicity, Fire for Rain article and correspondence, 1948; 1950; 1952 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 13)
  - Publicity, GE Internal Publications, 1950-1951; 1975 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 14)
  - Publicity, GE Internal Publications, 1950; 1975 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 15)
  - Publicity, GE News Bureau Photos and Articles, 1949; 1952 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 16)
  - Publicity, Journal of Applied Physics, 1947 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 17)
  - Publicity, News Clippings, 1947-1962 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 18)
  - Publicity, New Mexico Interview, 1952 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 19)
  - Publicity, Reviews and Advertising, 1979-1981; 1985 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 20)
  - Publicity, Science Illustrated, 1947 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 21)
  - Publicity Science Service, 1952 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 22)
  - Publicity, Scientific American Article, 1951 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 23)
  - Publicity, Weather Modification, 1947; 1952; 1962; 1966; 1973 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 24)
  - Reports, Cloud Seeding in Australia, Undated (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 25)
  - Reports, Cloud Seeding in Mexico, 1958 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 26)
  - Reports, Occasional Report 37 Technical Abstract, 1952 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 26)
  - Reports, Final Report ONR Project, 1953 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 27)
  - Reports, Final Report Project Cirrus, 1948 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 28)
  - Reports, Final Report Project Cirrus Part 1, Field, and Flight Experiments, 1953 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 29-30)
  - Reports, Final Report Project Cirrus, 1951; 1953 (Oversized 1)
  - Reports, GE Meteorological Studies, 1943-1945; 1947-1948 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 31)
  - Reports, GE Meteorological Studies, 1949-1951 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 32)
  - Reports, GE Meteorological Studies, 1952-1953; 1959; 1963; 1966 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 33)
  - Reports, GE Meteorological Studies, Undated (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 34)
  - Reports, Occassional Report 37 Technical Abstract, 1952 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 35)
  - Reports, Project Cirrus Associated Reports, 1950 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 36)
  - Reports, Project Cirrus Occasional Report 1-6, 1948 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 37)
  - Reports, Project Cirrus Occasional Report 7-12, 1948-1949 (Box 2 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 38)
  - Reports, Project Cirrus Occasional Report 13-17, 1949 (Box 3 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 1)
  - Reports, Project Cirrus Occasional Report 18-21, 1949-1950 (Box 3 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 2)
  - Reports, Project Cirrus Occasional Report 22-25, 1950 (Box 3 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 3)
  - Reports, Project Cirrus Occasional Report 26-29, 1951 (Box 3 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 4)
  - Reports, Project Cirrus Occasional Report 30-34, 1951-1952 (Box 3 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 5)
  - Reports, Project Cirrus Occasional Report 35-40, 1952; 1953 (Box 3 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 6)
  - Reports, Project Cirrus Operations Group report, 1950 (Box 3 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 7)
  - Reports, Project Cirrus Quarterly Report 1-5, 1947-1948 (Box 3 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 8)
  - Reports, Project Cirrus Quarterly Report Eight Quarter/ Number 13, 1950 (Box 4 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 1)
  - Reports, Vonnegut - Importance of Determining Various Variables Involved in Seeding Operations of Weather Control Experiments, Undated (Box 4 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 2)
  - Reprints, Artificial Stimulation of Rain at Kongwa, 1951 (Box 4 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 3)
  - Reprints, Atmospheric Conditions Necessary for Artificial Precipitation, 1949 (Box 4 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 4)
  - Reprints, Cloud Physics Letter and Abstract, 1950 (Box 4 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 5)
  - Reprints, Cloud Seeding Trails at Delhi During Monsoon Months July to September (1957-1959), 1961 (Box 4 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 6)
  - Reprints, The Control of Hurricans, 1955 (Box 4 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 7)
  - Reprints, Dessens and Maurin Mailed Articles, 1949 (Box 4 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 8)
  - Reprints, D.W. Pashley, Oriented Growth of Silver in Silver Halide Crystals, 1949 (Box 4 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 9)
  - Experiments with Silver Iodide Smokes in the Natural Atmosphere, 1950 (Box 4 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 10)
  - Reprints, Findelsen - Colloidal Meteorological Processes, 1938 (Box 4 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 11)
  - Reprints, Gathmann's US Patent for "A Method of Producing Rain-Fall", 1891 (Box 4 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 12)
  - Reprints, H.K. Weickmann - A Theory of the Formation of Ice Crystals, 1951 (Box 4 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 13)
  - Reprints, JAG Journal, 1949 (Box 4 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 14)
  - Reprints, Japanese Geophysical Science Articles and Correspondence, 1948 (Box 4 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 15)
  - Reprints, Journal of Applied Mathematics and Physics: Experimental Meteorology, 1950 (Box 4 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 16)
  - Reprints, J.Th.G. Overbeck Article, 1951 (Box 4 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 17)
  - Reprints, Kampe and Weickmann - AgI as a Freezing Nucleus, 1950 (Box 4 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 18)
  - Reprints, M. Tsuji - On the Rate of Evaporation and Condensation of Falling Drops, 1950 (Box 4 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 19)
  - Reprints, Motoi Kumai - Electron-Microscope Study of Snow-Crystal Nuclei, 1951 (Box 4 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 20)
  - Reprints, Physical Studies that would Improve our Knowledge of Meteorology, 1958 (Box 4 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 21)
  - Reprints, Recueil des Travaux Chimiques des Pays-Bas, 1951 (Box 4 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 22)
  - Reprints, Royal Meteorological Society, 1949-1950 (Box 4 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 23)
  - Reprints, Science - The Production of in a Cloud of Supercooled Water Droplets, 1946 (Box 4 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 24)
  - Reprints, Smoke Particles and Supercooled Clouds, Langmuir, 1948 (Box 4 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 25)
  - Reprints, Strock and Rauh - German Articles, 1935; 1941 (Box 4 (1-Project Cirrus), Folder 26)